right now it's not even hard to come up
with new ideas it's picking which one
they gave me like okay but I need to do
it in the moment so I can't write them
all up for hands
one of the ideas that I want to start
with one of the apples is to actually
create in the world is a online support
system so video chat where you're able
to meet with people who are have a
similar experience to you whether that's
a diagnosis or a condition of a family
member
a event that's happened in your lives in
your live like divorce or adoption or
failed adoption and being able to
connect with other people who are in
your similar situation in a time in
place that works for you because you're
doing it your own house and you can fill
what time works for you
so I'm available Tuesday afternoons is
there anyone else to hold Tuesday
afternoons and in small groups of 3 to 5
people like with the support group in
person but you don't need to be
geographically together and the reason
this project is so important to me is I
have a lot of reasons why it's a little
difficult for me to leave the house and
I want to have connection within my own
space and creating a platform for that
where I can say hey I want it right now
I'm discussing in Black Mirror with a
bunch of other a bunch of other two
other moms on Wednesday night we watch
the episode we discuss it and a lot of
its of course like how was your last
week can you get to be more friends and
feel connected to people that I don't
feel on Facebook when someone's just got
a little thumbnail and their name I
don't know who they are once I've got
them in person then that means something
to me and in person I mean also on video
chat feels like I've met them in person
and so there is an infinite number of
ways to use that service but as people
in my life have are going through
struggles and I don't have the energy or
the ability to be
who they all come to all of the time
it's like seek out a support group well
that's easier said than done when one it
doesn't necessarily exist and two might
be hard to fit into your schedule or
threaten people all over Canada or the
United States or the world that you
would need to be able to make a group
just discuss that about discuss your
issue with or discuss it in a language
that you speak so having an online
support system where you can go on say
here is my what my disability or my
condition here are people like and it
can start with something a lot simpler
I mean I'm part of a part of that I've
went once I'm going this Friday to buy
keep a seat the days but a queer people
with disability support group and it's
different than of course just a queer
support group or just a disability
support group it's like that
intersectionality of those two coming
together and that's important and so
[Music]
finding that space online it might not
start that way it might be like okay
just people with disabilities living
with chronic pain living with chronic um
how's that Olivia with diabetes living
with like it branches off as much as it
needs to because if you're only having
groups of 3 to 5 it's like starts with
hey who else has a disability want to
discuss it is it's a pros of it I mean
whatever whatever happens to be and have
guiding questions and ways to because
this isn't a formal support group
there's not a therapist or it's just
people getting together and discussing
their story and how and talking about it
and just that act helps having someone
listen who's in the same boat or has
been in the same boat it's so important
and so the one of the reasons I want
this to be the first project that's
actually created is I believe that it
becomes the other projects as you're
able to because it's not just about
support groups the more you're able to
say hey I would like to discuss global
hunger my own family's hunger poverty
whatever it happens to be
you then have a group of people
discussing it then I think very
organically grows into how do we solve
these problems how do we collectively
discuss them and I can very much see
using an online group chat platform to
create the other ideas because you have
people who care about an idea and can
therefore start a chat group on how to
make it actually happen and it's one of
the ones that has a direct impact on my
life right away because as I was saying
there's a lot of reasons I can't leave
the home my house I have a disability
that keeps me in the house a lot of the
time it's hard for me to go up for many
hours
it's very fatiguing it's also on the
single mom so I have a lot of time with
my child home asleep or I can't go out
but I can have a conversation with
someone or when she's in daycare I could
have a conversation with someone and
yeah so by and just by personality I
kind of like chatting with people online
more so than going out to a to allow a
coffee shop and meeting someone and it
works for me it makes me feel connected
in a way that talking on the phone or
typing doesn't doesn't make me feel and
a lot of the services that are already
out there don't do what this is doing
that I want this to be like Meetup
but online so meetup is all about
meeting offline through online and this
is about meeting online through online
so saying here is the link to where
we're discussing on here's the time
here's the language here's what were
discussing and here's the group we're
discussing it with people can be added
it's a fairly simple program because I'm
not going to create the video chat
itself I'm going to use the ones that
are available on skype except to add
people but there's one called up here in
there seems to work it's not perfect but
these are my work with what you got
so that is Apple number two which will
end up being actual Apple number one or
applesauce number one what I'm creating
with the apples and moving forward with
that so creating an online support
system for people thank you